Guide to the Atlantic and Western Railway Company Records, 1905-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Atlantic and Western Railway Company records 1905-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Atlantic and Western Railway Company
55.7 Linear Feet 41,774 Items
North Carolina short-line railroad company established in 1896 and still in operation as of 2008.
Correspondence, accounts, financial reports, ledgers, memoranda, publications, and other records (chiefly 1918-1960), of a short-line railway operating between Sanford and Lillington, N.C., in Lee and Harnett counties. Includes communications from the American Short Line Railroad Association and the Association of American Railroads.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Atlantic and Western Railway Company Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1975.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
American Short Line Railroad Association
Association of American Railroads
Railroads -- North Carolina -- Records and correspondence
Railroads -- North Carolina -- History
Lee County (N.C.)--Economic conditions
Harnett County (N.C.)--Economic conditions
Sanford (N.C.)--Economic conditions
Lillington (N.C.)--Economic conditions
Contents of Collection
- Financial Papers Series, 1912-1966, (7 boxes)
  - Notes and Information (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1912-1966
  - Financial reports
    - Annual reports, 1914-1918
    - Accounting reports, 1917 (Box 2)
    - Accountant's reports, 1929-1943
    - Statements of operations, 1926-1960
    - Annual reports to Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 3)
      - 1913-1938
      - 1939-1949 (Box 4)
      - 1950-1956 (Box 5)
    - Annual reports to N.C. Utilities Commission
      - 1934-1942 (Box 5)
      - 1943-1959 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- Files Series, 1907-1968, (50 boxes)
  - 1907-1917
    - H-Q, 103-200 (Box 8)
    - 304-624 (Box 9)
  - 1918
    - A-R, 114-500 (Box 9)
    - 518-612 (Box 10)
  - 1919
    - E, 114-500, U.S. Railroad Administration (Box 11)
  - 1920
    - A and S, 114-248 (Box 11)
    - 254-583 (Box 12)
  - 1921
    - 102-303 (Box 12)
    - 308-685 (Box 13)
  - 1922
    - 150-579 (Box 13)
  - 1923
    - R-102 (Box 13)
    - 122-619 (Box 14)
    - 624-691 (Box 15)
  - 1924
    - 223-371 (Box 15)
    - 401-640 (Box 16)
  - 1925
    - Sullivan, 483-624 (Box 16)
  - 1926
    - 154-218 (Box 16)
    - 243-676 (Box 17)
  - 1927
    - Sullivan, 194
    - 215-651 (Box 18)
  - 1929
    - Campbell, Huffer, Sullivan, 243-660 (Box 19)
    - 102-624 (Box 20)
  - 1930
    - Campbell, Huffer, Sullivan, 102-483 (Box 21)
    - 500-676 (Box 22)
  - 1931
    - Campbell, Huffer, 102-343
    - 344-681 (Box 23)
  - 1932
    - Campbell, Huffer, Sullivan, 154-521 (Box 24)
    - 533-702 (Box 25)
  - 1933
    - Campbell, Huffer, Sullivan, 143-309
    - 344-624 (Box 26)
    - 651-750 (Box 27)
  - 1934
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, Sullivan, 143-344
    - 347-751 (Box 28)
  - 1935
    - Campbell, Huffer, Sullivan, 134-344 (Box 29)
    - 344-751 (Box 30)
  - 1936
    - Campbell, Chase, Huffer, 143-243
    - 271-705 (Box 31)
  - 1937
    - Chase National Bank, Huffer, 143-344 (Box 32)
    - 344-744 (Box 33)
  - 1938
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 143-500 (Box 34)
    - 533-751 (Box 35)
  - 1939
    - Campbell, Chase, Huffer, 143-271 (Box 35)
    - 298-705 (Box 36)
    - Campbell, Huffer, 102-343
  - 1940
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 143-507 (Box 37)
    - 533-735 (Box 38)
  - 1941
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 128-300 (Box 38)
    - 344-752 (Box 39)
  - 1942
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 143-475 (Box 40)
    - 507-742 (Box 41)
  - 1943
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 101-344B (Box 42)
    - 347-708 (Box 43)
  - 1944
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, Huffer, 143-271 (Box 43)
    - 293-735 (Box 44)
  - 1945
    - Campbell, Chase National Bank, 194-723 (Box 45)
  - 1946
    - 194-394 (Box 45)
    - 404-735 (Box 46)
  - 1947
    - Chase National Bank, Bank of Broadway, National Bank of Sanford, 114-385 (Box 46)
    - 404-723 (Box 47)
  - 1948
    - Bank of Broadway, National Bank of Sanford, 194-385 (Box 47)
    - 404-723 (Box 48)
    - Bank of Broadway, National Bank of Sanford, 154-298
  - 1949
    - 344-723 (Box 49)
  - 1950
    - Bank of Broadway, National Bank of Sanford, 194-344 (Box 49)
    - 344A-723 (Box 50)
  - 1951
    - Bank of Broadway, National Bank of Sanford, 194-271 (Box 50)
    - 298-752 (Box 51)
  - 1952
    - 194-72 (Box 52)
  - 1953
    - 176-344B (Box 52)
    - 351-723 (Box 53)
  - 1954
    - 194-723 (Box 53)
  - 1955
    - 194-676 (Box 54)
  - 1956
    - 194-344 (Box 54)
    - 385-676 (Box 55)
  - 1957
    - 194-752 (Box 55)
  - 1958 (Box 56)
    - 194-752
  - 1959
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 194-676 (Box 56)
  - 1960
    - 194-723 (Box 57)
    - Files, 1961-1968
- Periodicals Series, 1928-1966, (5 boxes)
  - CrossTie Bulletin, 1937, 1941-1944 (Box 58)
  - Railroad Data, 1928-1933
  - Weekly Information Bulletin (Box 59)
    - Index, 1933-1936
    - Bulletins
      - 1933-1936 Sept.
      - 1936 Oct.-1938 June (Box 60)
    - Index, 1938
    - Bulletins, 1938 July-1942 June (Box 61)
    - Index 1938
    - Bulletins, 1942 July-1946, 1951-1953, 1966 (Box 62)
    - Index, 1945
- Miscellany Series, (1 box)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Papers (Box 63)
  - Safety posters
  - Passes
  - Timetables
- Volumes Series, 1913-1967, (2 boxes)
  - Accounts Payable, 1914-1928 (Box 64)
  - Accounts Receivable, 1913-1952
  - Authority for Expenditures, 1917-1930
  - Traffic and Car Service Ledger, 1926-1939
  - American Short Line Railroad Association (Box 65)
    - Agenda and Proceeding, 1938-1967
    - Publication, 1924-1956
- Oversize Materials
  Consists of blueprints; charts for the Association of American Railroads; correspondence printed on flyers; and engineering, equipment and land reports.
  - Oversize items (Opaperfolder OF1)